{"classes":["COMMODITY","DATE","GPE","GPE_ORG","LOC","MONEY","ORG","NORP","PERSON","QUANTITY","REL","STRUCTURE","TITLE","TRIBE","UNKNOWN","VESSEL"],"annotations":[["\" Urban \" population and \" urban \" life.—In approaching the subject of races and tribes among the people of 'Irāq, we may discard the distinction adopted above for purposes of numerical calculation and adopt another more suitable to our new topic—one, namely, between \" urban \" and \" rural \" population. By \" urban \" population are meant here not only the residents of towns, properly so called, but also those of permanent villages; the \" rural \" population is taken to consist of the semi-nomads already mentioned, whose dwellings are huts or even tents, and of Bedouins pure and simple. The \" urban \" population, in what follows below, is thus very far from being identical with the \" fixed \" population above; and similarly there is no correspondence between the \" nomadic \" and \" rural \" populations.",{"entities":[[104,109,"GPE"],[552,560,"TRIBE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["The inhabitants of the towns and permanent villages, who thus form by themselves a natural division of the people, may be subdivided according to race into Arabs, Persians, Jews, Turks, Kurds, Chaldæans, Armenians and Sabians, besides Asiatic and European foreigners.",{"entities":[[156,161,"NORP"],[163,171,"NORP"],[173,177,"REL"],[179,184,"NORP"],[186,191,"NORP"],[193,202,"NORP"],[204,213,"NORP"],[218,225,"NORP"],[236,267,"NORP"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["Arabs form the bulk of all the urban communities in 'Irāq with the two important exceptions of Baghdād City and the towns of Karbala and Kadhimain: in the first of these they are outnumbered by Jews, and in the other two by Persians. The distinctions of the urban Arabs among themselves are mainly religious and will be noticed further on; but a large proportion of them are descended from the rural tribes, dealt with in a later paragraph, and to some extent preserve their characteristics. The Arab of 'Irāq is not fanatical, but he is grasping in money matters and frequently overreaches himself by the extravagance of his own demands; he labours also under a rooted disinclination for hard work.",{"entities":[[0,5,"NORP"],[52,57,"GPE"],[95,107,"GPE"],[125,132,"GPE"],[137,146,"GPE"],[194,198,"REL"],[224,233,"NORP"],[264,269,"NORP"],[496,500,"NORP"],[504,509,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["At Karbala Town, and at Kādhimain Town as well, Persians predominate in numbers over all other races. There is a considerable Persian colony in Baghdād City and one-eighth of the population of Basrah Town and a considerable proportion of that of Tawairīj are believed to be Persian; Persians engaged in retail trade are found even in such minor places as Rumaithah, 'Alī-al-Gharbi and Qal'at Sālih. Many of the Persians are Turkish subjects; but they are generally unpopular with the Turks, and some of them maintain on their part a covert religious and political opposition to the Ottoman Government, especially at Karbala and Najaf.",{"entities":[[3,15,"GPE"],[24,38,"GPE"],[126,133,"NORP"],[144,156,"GPE"],[193,204,"GPE"],[246,254,"GPE"],[274,281,"NORP"],[283,291,"NORP"],[355,364,"GPE"],[367,381,"GPE"],[386,399,"GPE"],[412,420,"NORP"],[425,432,"NORP"],[485,490,"NORP"],[583,601,"ORG"],[617,624,"GPE"],[629,634,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["The Jews are from every point of view an extremely important element in the population, and in the city of Baghdād they are believed to outnumber the Turks and even the Arabs. In 'Irāq, which contains the tombs of Ezra and Ezekiel and reaches to within a short distance of the tomb of Daniel, the Jews are surrounded by monuments of the Captivity, and this may account for the exceptional bigotry and devotion to the minutiæ of their law which they here display. They are almost entirely engaged in trade and money-lending, and many of them are altogether absorbed in these pursuits; but some of them are men of high and honourable character, in every way worthy of the distinguished and responsible positions to which they not infrequently attain. Many of them begin life as hawkers of stockings and such wares; all marry young and receive some capital at marriage from their fathers-in-law; when the latter are too poor to pay, the dowry or Muhr مهر is subscribed by their neighbours. The trade of Baghdād is passing every year more under Jewish control; and many Jews now visit England, and some of them even reside there as business agents for partners or relations. The native Christian merchants of Baghdād have mostly disappeared during the last 15 years in consequence of Jewish competition, and already Muhammadan merchants are taking Jews into partnership as a measure of self-defence; the Muhammadans, however, are still able to hold their own to some extent in the up-country trade carried on from Baghdād. The leading native firms at Basrah are Jewish also. Jews are found at various other places throughout the country such as 'Amārah Town, where they have a synagogue and two rabbis; Kūt-al-Amārah, where they have a synagogue; Nāsiriyah, Sūq-ash-Shuyūkh, Hai, 'Alī-al'-Gharbi and Qal'at Sālih. They venerate the tomb of Ezekiel at Kifl and many of them are buried there.",{"entities":[[4,8,"REL"],[107,114,"GPE"],[150,155,"NORP"],[169,175,"NORP"],[179,184,"GPE"],[205,230,"STRUCTURE"],[277,291,"STRUCTURE"],[297,301,"REL"],[1000,1007,"GPE"],[1041,1047,"REL"],[1066,1070,"REL"],[1081,1088,"GPE"],[1182,1191,"REL"],[1205,1212,"GPE"],[1253,1261,"QUANTITY"],[1280,1286,"REL"],[1312,1322,"REL"],[1344,1348,"REL"],[1400,1411,"REL"],[1510,1518,"GPE"],[1547,1553,"GPE"],[1558,1564,"REL"],[1571,1575,"REL"],[1641,1653,"GPE"],[1673,1682,"STRUCTURE"],[1699,1712,"GPE"],[1732,1741,"STRUCTURE"],[1743,1752,"GPE"],[1754,1769,"GPE"],[1771,1774,"GPE"],[1776,1791,"GPE"],[1796,1809,"GPE"],[1828,1843,"STRUCTURE"],[1847,1851,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}