{"classes":["COMMODITY","DATE","GPE","GPE_ORG","LOC","MONEY","ORG","NORP","PERSON","QUANTITY","REL","STRUCTURE","TITLE","TRIBE","UNKNOWN","VESSEL"],"annotations":[["Physical geography and character.—-'Irāq is a plain of alluvial clay, unrelieved by a single range, hill or natural eminence of the slightest importance. On the east, however, the plain is dominated by the hills of the Persian district of Pusht-i-Kūh which, snow-clad in midwinter approach within about 30 miles of the Tigris at 'Ali-al-Gharbi and are in full view, running nearly parallel to the river, all the way between the towns of 'Amārah and Kūt-al-Amārah.",{"entities":[[23,40,"GPE"],[239,250,"GPE"],[303,311,"QUANTITY"],[319,325,"LOC"],[329,343,"GPE"],[437,444,"GPE"],[449,462,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["The chief features of 'Irāq are, of course, the great rivers Euphrates and Tigris, upon which the prosperity and even the habitability of the entire country depend. Minor but still important features are the Diyālah, a left bank tributary of the Tigris a short way below Baghdād; the Shatt-al-Hindīyah, formerly a canal but now a substitute for the dried-up reach of the Euphrates between Musaiyib and Samāwah; the channel, known as the Shatt-al-Gharāf, which connects the Tigris at Kūt-al-Amārah with the Euphrates at Nāsiriyah and Hammār; the enormous marshes upon the lower course of both Euphrates and Tigris from Qūrnah up to the towns of 'Amārah and Nāsiriyah respectively; the swamps in which the Daghārah canal has its ending, and those which are said to have submerged a large part of the country between the Shatt-al-Gharāf, Tigris and Euphrates; the Jahalah which draws off a large proportion of the Tigris water at 'Amārah Town, restoring part of it to the Shatt-al-'Arab viâ the Suwaib, together with the swamps to which this canal gives rise: finally a long, but narrow, saline marsh reaching apparently most of the way from Mandali to Kūt-al-Amārah upon the Tigris, of which the large swamp near Jassān جسّان town, known as Hor Jassān, is perhaps a part.",{"entities":[[22,27,"GPE"],[61,70,"LOC"],[75,81,"LOC"],[208,215,"LOC"],[246,252,"LOC"],[271,278,"GPE"],[284,301,"LOC"],[371,380,"LOC"],[389,397,"GPE"],[402,409,"GPE"],[437,452,"LOC"],[473,479,"LOC"],[483,496,"GPE"],[506,515,"LOC"],[519,528,"GPE"],[533,539,"GPE"],[592,601,"LOC"],[606,612,"LOC"],[618,624,"GPE"],[644,651,"GPE"],[656,665,"GPE"],[704,718,"LOC"],[818,833,"LOC"],[835,841,"LOC"],[846,855,"LOC"],[861,868,"LOC"],[911,917,"LOC"],[927,939,"GPE"],[969,983,"LOC"],[992,998,"LOC"],[1139,1146,"GPE"],[1150,1163,"GPE"],[1173,1179,"LOC"],[1211,1228,"GPE"],[1239,1249,"LOC"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["Two vegetable products, natural but possessing a commercial value, are colocynth or Handhal حنظل and Sūs سوس or liquorice. The colocynth occurs everywhere and is obtained in large quantities from the waste country between Baghdād and Hillah; but it is inferior to the Syrian colocynth, and the dried pulp only is exported instead of the whole fruit. The trade in liquorice is dealt with in one of the paragraphs, on trade below. The liquorice plant grows chiefly in river bends, on the concave side of the curves, and is said never to be found at more than two miles distance from the water's edge; it requires a good deal of moisture and benefits by occasional floods. Its maximum height is about 10 feet, but on the average it does not exceed 4 or 5. Liquoriee wood is a staple article of fuel at Baghdād.",{"entities":[[71,80,"COMMODITY"],[84,91,"COMMODITY"],[101,104,"COMMODITY"],[112,122,"COMMODITY"],[127,136,"COMMODITY"],[222,229,"GPE"],[234,240,"GPE"],[275,284,"COMMODITY"],[363,372,"COMMODITY"],[433,442,"COMMODITY"],[557,566,"QUANTITY"],[698,705,"QUANTITY"],[745,749,"QUANTITY"],[753,762,"COMMODITY"],[799,806,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["Climate and health.—The climate of 'Irāq is on the whole not unhealthy, but it may be described as extreme, for the temperature in the shade ranges at Baghdād City from a minimum of 18.6°F. in winter to a maximum of 123° in summer. December, January and February are cold, crisp, and even bracing months, during which some rain falls; March and April are warm and unsettled, with occasional thunder and dust-storms; May and June are hot but fine, often with a refreshing north-west wind or Shamāl at night; in July, August and September the heat is excessive and almost insupportable, driving the inhabitants of the towns to live in subterranean rooms or Sardābs سرداب by day and upon the roofs of their houses from sunset to sunrise; during October the heat begins to abate, and in November the weather becomes cool again. More precise details of temperature and rainfall will be found in the article on Baghdād City, the only place in 'Irāq for which exact statistics exist.",{"entities":[[35,40,"GPE"],[151,163,"GPE"],[182,189,"QUANTITY"],[216,220,"QUANTITY"],[232,240,"DATE"],[242,249,"DATE"],[254,262,"DATE"],[335,340,"DATE"],[345,350,"DATE"],[416,419,"DATE"],[424,428,"DATE"],[510,514,"DATE"],[516,522,"DATE"],[527,536,"DATE"],[742,749,"DATE"],[783,791,"DATE"],[905,917,"GPE"],[937,942,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["In 'Irāq the prevailing winds are those from the north-west and north; but calm weather is the rule. High temperatures accompany the east wind or Sharqi when it blows in the months of June, July and August; and the south wind is invariably oppressive and is generally accompanied by dust.",{"entities":[[3,8,"GPE"],[184,188,"DATE"],[190,194,"DATE"],[199,205,"DATE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}