{"classes":["COMMODITY","DATE","GPE","GPE_ORG","LOC","MONEY","ORG","NORP","PERSON","QUANTITY","REL","STRUCTURE","TITLE","TRIBE","UNKNOWN","VESSEL"],"annotations":[["'IRĀQ",{"entities":[[0,5,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["The ancient name 'Iraq —of which the etymology, or at least the meaning in the present case, is doubtful3 —is used by the Ottomah Grovernment to denote the country of the lower Euphrates and Tigris—the richest and most valuable in the whole basin of the Persian Gulf—which is comprised in the Turkish Wilāyats or provinces of Baghdād and Basrah. In British official terminology Turkish 'Irāq, with the addition of the more northern Wilāyat of Mūsal موصل, is conventionally known as \" Turkish Arabia \"; but the expression is an unfortunate one, for it obviously suggests the Red Sea provinces of Yaman and Hijāz rather than Mesopotamia which is no part, either physically or politically, of the Arabian peninsula.",{"entities":[[17,22,"GPE"],[122,141,"ORG"],[171,201,"LOC"],[254,272,"LOC"],[293,309,"GPE"],[326,333,"GPE"],[338,345,"GPE"],[378,391,"GPE"],[432,448,"GPE"],[483,497,"GPE"],[572,579,"LOC"],[593,598,"GPE"],[603,608,"GPE"],[692,709,"LOC"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["It remains to mention a few of the principal books, etc., which may be consulted, in regard to 'Irāq. The more valuable of the older authorities are: Ainsworth's Researches , 1838; Chesney's Expedition for the Survey of the Rivers Euphrates and Tigris , 1850; Layard's Nineveh and Babylon , 1853; Loftus' Travels and Researches , 1857; Bombay Selections, XVIII , 1857; Chesney's Narrative of the Euphrates Expedition , 1868; and Layard's Early Adventures , 1887. Recent authorities on the topography, population, agriculture, etc., of the country are not numerous: the best are the Gazetteer of Baghdād , 1889; Cuinet's La Turquie d 'Asie (Vol. III), 1894; and the Turkish Sālnāmahs or official almanacs, published periodically, of which that of 1903 for the Baghdād Wilāyat and that of 1898 for the Basrah Wilāyat—the latest available—have been utilised in the compilation of the present Gazetteer. A Reconnaissance Report , 1904, by Captain H. Smyth, contains much general information and deals particularly with communications, transport and the probable line of the projected Baghdād Railway: it will be found in the Political Proceedings of the Government of India fur February 1905. In all matters of Turkish administration the highest authority is Mr. G. Young's Corps de Droit Ottoman , 1905: this invaluable work was unfortunately brought too late to the knowledge of the writer to be consulted in writing the Gazetteer. The best source of information in regard to military organisation is Colonel F. R. Maunaell's Handbook of the Turkish Army , 1904; and the annual Consular Reports for Baghdād and Basrah deal fully with the subject of trade. Mr. G. Le Strange's books Baghdād during the Abbasid Caliphate , 1900, and Lands of the Eastern Caliphate , 1905, have superseded all other and less comprehensive works on the geography of' Irāq in mediæval times. Some information about the country in general and about particular places will be found in the Foreign Proceedings of the Government of India for February 1905. See also the Report of the German Railway Commission in the Proceedings for May 1901.",{"entities":[[95,101,"GPE"],[150,159,"PERSON"],[174,178,"DATE"],[180,187,"PERSON"],[223,250,"LOC"],[252,256,"DATE"],[258,264,"PERSON"],[267,274,"GPE"],[279,286,"GPE"],[288,292,"DATE"],[294,300,"PERSON"],[326,330,"DATE"],[332,338,"GPE"],[358,362,"DATE"],[364,371,"PERSON"],[391,400,"LOC"],[413,417,"DATE"],[423,429,"PERSON"],[450,455,"DATE"],[588,595,"GPE"],[597,601,"DATE"],[603,609,"PERSON"],[615,622,"GPE"],[643,647,"DATE"],[738,742,"DATE"],[751,766,"GPE"],[779,783,"DATE"],[792,810,"GPE"],[917,921,"DATE"],[926,942,"PERSON"],[1071,1078,"GPE"],[1141,1160,"ORG"],[1165,1179,"DATE"],[1246,1258,"PERSON"],[1285,1289,"DATE"],[1489,1511,"PERSON"],[1530,1542,"ORG"],[1544,1548,"DATE"],[1586,1593,"GPE"],[1598,1604,"GPE"],[1643,1660,"PERSON"],[1669,1676,"GPE"],[1688,1705,"ORG"],[1707,1711,"DATE"],[1730,1747,"ORG"],[1749,1753,"DATE"],[1831,1835,"GPE"],[1977,1996,"ORG"],[2001,2015,"DATE"],[2043,2068,"ORG"],[2096,2100,"DATE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["Boundaries.—'Irāq is bounded on the west by the Shāmlyah Desert, on the south by the frontier of the Kuwait Principality and by the waters of the Persian Gulf. On the east its limit is the Persian border; and on the north our detailed inquiries will not extend beyond the town of Kādhimain on the Tigris.",{"entities":[[0,17,"GPE"],[48,63,"LOC"],[101,120,"GPE"],[146,159,"LOC"],[189,203,"LOC"],[280,289,"GPE"],[297,303,"LOC"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["The Porte probably regard the Shāmīyah Desert as embraced in the Wilāyats of Baghdād and Basrah; but their authority over the nomad tribes inhabiting it is so slight that to treat any of the country to the west of the settled Euphrates valley as attached, even administratively, to 'Irāq would be a mistake: the most outlying Turkish stations, civil or military, upon this side are Shifāthah, Najaf Town, Rahabah and Zubair Town.",{"entities":[[4,9,"ORG"],[30,45,"LOC"],[65,95,"GPE"],[226,242,"LOC"],[282,287,"GPE"],[382,391,"GPE"],[393,403,"GPE"],[405,412,"GPE"],[417,428,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["The exact position of the southern frontier is discussed in the article on the Kuwait Principality, and in this direction the most advanced Turkish outposts recognised by the British Government are those at Safwān and Umm Qasr; His Majesty's Government do not admit the title of the Porte to Būbiyān island, where a small detachment of Turkish troops is at present stationed.",{"entities":[[79,98,"GPE"],[175,193,"ORG"],[207,213,"GPE"],[218,226,"GPE"],[228,239,"TITLE"],[283,288,"ORG"],[292,306,"GPE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}