{"classes":["PERSON","TRIBE","GPE_ORG","REL","LOC","QUANTITY","MONEY","VESSEL","GPE"],"annotations":[["Mr. James Morley",{"entities":[[0,16,"PERSON"]]}],["Resident",{"entities":[]}],["Bushire",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["by the Dolphin Schooner, your express boat is arrived with your original letters of",{"entities":[[7,23,"VESSEL"]]}],["8th and 9th Instant, and a Duplicate of the 24 of October; original of which, has since",{"entities":[]}],["thing in the disputes between Carim Caun and the Shaikhs of Boushire and Bah",{"entities":[[30,40,"PERSON"],[49,68,"PERSON"]]}],["Companys property being plundered in case of an attack at Bushire by the persians",{"entities":[[58,65,"GPE"]]}],["Ormuso expedition is over, should we think it necessary, we will station acco",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"]]}],["Cruizers at Bushire, as you now seem to think their presence is absolutely nec",{"entities":[[12,19,"GPE"]]}],["beginning before Shaik Ice his return from Bahreen, which we do not imagine",{"entities":[[17,26,"PERSON"],[43,50,"GPE"]]}],["will be, before our Cruizers return from Ormuso.",{"entities":[[41,47,"GPE"]]}],["Your supplying the managers on the Ormuse",{"entities":[[35,41,"GPE"]]}],["Expedition with money and a few peices of Woollens was very proper.",{"entities":[[26,50,"QUANTITY"]]}],["be indebted to Mr Bonnyear, he has only to draw bills on this Ag for there",{"entities":[[15,26,"PERSON"]]}],["the early arrival of intelligence at Bombay; to have had an account of the loss received by",{"entities":[[37,43,"GPE"]]}],["our Superiors before their Cruizers may have sailed for the Gulph, might have been of the",{"entities":[[60,65,"LOC"]]}],["we now dispatch the Salamander to Bombay; Lieutenant Gages stay at Bushire is",{"entities":[[20,30,"VESSEL"],[34,40,"GPE"],[42,58,"PERSON"],[67,74,"GPE"]]}],["limited to four and twenty hours; on no account therefore detain him longer than that",{"entities":[[11,32,"QUANTITY"]]}],["India are all ready, as you must conclude we should dispatch there as soon after",{"entities":[[0,5,"GPE"]]}],["the Salamanders arrival at Bussora as possible.",{"entities":[[4,15,"VESSEL"],[27,34,"GPE"]]}],["We should have you examine Mr Bowye",{"entities":[[27,35,"PERSON"]]}],["application to Bombay for further directions in this manner we act regarding",{"entities":[[15,21,"GPE"]]}],["Mr Lyster who has died intestate.",{"entities":[[0,9,"PERSON"]]}],["It is improper that Bushire should",{"entities":[[20,27,"GPE_ORG"]]}],["be without two covenanted servants, we have appointed Mr. John Yoakly Botham",{"entities":[[54,76,"PERSON"]]}]]}