{
  "classes": [
    "PERSON",
    "TRIBE",
    "GPE_ORG",
    "REL",
    "LOC",
    "GPE",
    "QUANTITY",
    "MONEY",
    "VESSEL",
    "TITLE",
    "ORG",
    "UNKNOWN"
  ],
  "annotations": [
    ["Mr. James Morley", { "entities": [[0, 16, "PERSON"]] }],
    ["Resident", { "entities": [] }],
    ["Bushire", { "entities": [[0, 7, "GPE"]] }],
    ["Sir", { "entities": [] }],
    ["Since our last letter to you of the 9 Novemb", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "by the Dolphin Schooner, your express boat is arrived with your original letters of",
      { "entities": [[7, 23, "VESSEL"]] }
    ],
    [
      "8th and 9th Instant, and a Duplicate of the 24 of October; original of which, has since",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "been received, We have also received your General Books.",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    ["It is not in our power at present to do any¬", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "thing in the disputes between Carim Caun and the Shaikhs of Boushire and Bah",
      {
        "entities": [
          [30, 40, "PERSON"],
          [49, 76, "PERSON"]
        ]
      }
    ],
    [
      "writing to him just now, we do not imagine would have the least good effect; if",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "are ordered by our Superiors to enter into fresh negociations with the Caun, Bush",
      { "entities": [[71, 75, "TITLE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "of course will not be neglected, and untill then, we shall avoid interfering in their",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "any further than what is immediately relative to our own Factory and comme",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    ["We hope your fears on account the Honble", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "Companys property being plundered in case of an attack at Bushire by the persians",
      { "entities": [[58, 65, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "prove groundless. You will know our Cruizers are otherwise employed: when the",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "Ormuso expedition is over, should we think it necessary, we will station acco",
      { "entities": [[0, 6, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "Cruizers at Bushire, as you now seem to think their presence is absolutely nec",
      { "entities": [[12, 19, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "for the preservation of the Honble Companys effects: there is no probability",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "beginning before Shaik Ice his return from Bahreen, which we do not imagine",
      {
        "entities": [
          [17, 26, "PERSON"],
          [43, 50, "GPE"]
        ]
      }
    ],
    [
      "will be, before our Cruizers return from Ormuso.",
      { "entities": [[41, 47, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "In our letter by the Dolphin we have",
      { "entities": [[21, 28, "VESSEL"]] }
    ],
    [
      "to you what is proper regarding your sending us the Woollens we have indented for.",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "Your supplying the managers on the Ormuse",
      { "entities": [[35, 41, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "Expedition with money and a few peices of Woollens was very proper.",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    ["Whatever money the Honble Company", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "be indebted to Mr Bonnyear, he has only to draw bills on this Ag for there",
      { "entities": [[15, 26, "PERSON"]] }
    ],
    [
      "of it, should not the Cash we have already remitted you",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    ["pay the amount borrowed of him.", { "entities": [] }],
    ["We are informed that", { "entities": [] }],
    ["", { "entities": [] }],
    ["", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "account of the sad Catrastrophe; never think about the expense, when so much depends on",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "the early arrival of intelligence at Bombay; to have had an account of the loss received by",
      { "entities": [[37, 43, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "our Superiors before their Cruizers may have sailed for the Gulph, might have been of the",
      { "entities": [[60, 65, "LOC"]] }
    ],
    ["utmost consequences-", { "entities": [] }],
    ["To convey this melancholy intelligence", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "we now dispatch the Salamander to Bombay; Lieutenant Gages stay at Bushire is",
      {
        "entities": [
          [20, 30, "VESSEL"],
          [34, 40, "GPE"],
          [42, 58, "PERSON"],
          [67, 74, "GPE"]
        ]
      }
    ],
    [
      "limited to four and twenty hours; on no account therefore detain him longer than that",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "time, but as much short of it as possible, we make no doubt but your dispatch for",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "India are all ready, as you must conclude we should dispatch there as soon after",
      { "entities": [[0, 5, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "the Salamanders arrival at Bussora as possible.",
      {
        "entities": [
          [4, 15, "VESSEL"],
          [27, 34, "GPE"]
        ]
      }
    ],
    [
      "We should have you examine Mr Bowye",
      { "entities": [[27, 35, "PERSON"]] }
    ],
    [
      "Papers for a Will: if you find one of course you will act in compliance thereto: but",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "if he has died intestate let his perishables be sold, the remainder sealed up, and make",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "application to Bombay for further directions in this manner we act regarding",
      { "entities": [[15, 21, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    ["Mr Lyster who has died intestate.", { "entities": [[0, 9, "PERSON"]] }],
    ["It is improper that Bushire should", { "entities": [[20, 27, "GPE"]] }],
    [
      "be without two covenanted servants, we have appointed Mr. John Yoakly Botham",
      { "entities": [[54, 76, "PERSON"]] }
    ],
    [
      "Wuter to your assistance, who has received his Salary to the 1 of July last and",
      { "entities": [[0, 5, "PERSON"]] }
    ],
    ["dietmoney to the 31st. of this month_", { "entities": [] }],
    ["We are very much pleased that the Persian", { "entities": [] }],
    [
      "troops are withdrawn from the Country about Bushire, and hope that your Shaikhs",
      {
        "entities": [
          [44, 51, "GPE"],
          [72, 79, "TITLE"]
        ]
      }
    ],
    [
      "arrival at Schiras will take off every impedement that our trade has long laboured",
      { "entities": [[11, 18, "GPE"]] }
    ],
    [
      "under; - we are very much in want of Cash, and shall be very glad when the",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    [
      "State of your Treasury will admit of your consigning us any; when it will, take",
      { "entities": [] }
    ],
    ["the first secure conveyance for doing it", { "entities": [] }],
    ["We again recommend the shortest detention", { "entities": [] }],
    ["possible of the Salamander, and are", { "entities": [] }],
    ["", { "entities": [] }]
  ]
}
