{"classes":["COMMODITY","DATE","GPE","GPE_ORG","LOC","MONEY","ORG","NORP","PERSON","QUANTITY","REL","STRUCTURE","TITLE","TRIBE","UNKNOWN","VESSEL"],"annotations":[["Bushier you did cause her to proceed without delay to the Bar of Bussora River thence",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"],[65,78,"LOC"]]}],["to dispatch one of the boats to maghiel with the Packets for Me & for the Resident at",{"entities":[[32,39,"GPE"],[74,82,"TITLE"]]}],["Bagdad under the charge of a Lieutenant or Midshipman and having effected that",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"]]}],["would probably have secured the receipt by Me of those Packets on or before the 25 Ultimo",{"entities":[[80,89,"DATE"]]}],["and it could not have exposed either yourself or Mr Bruce or the Honble Companys",{"entities":[[49,57,"PERSON"],[65,80,"ORG"]]}],["Your own will and Pesidence whether the truly unfortunate event which occasioned the",{"entities":[[18,27,"TITLE"]]}],["Ternates voyage from the Presidency to the Gulph became known or remained",{"entities":[[0,8,"VESSEL"],[25,35,"ORG"],[43,48,"LOC"]]}],["a Secret at Bushire untill her Return to you",{"entities":[[12,19,"GPE"]]}],["On the Receipt if your letter beforementioned of the 21Ultimo",{"entities":[[53,61,"DATE"]]}],["I formed an intention of immeadately dispatching the Panther to Bushire in order",{"entities":[[53,60,"VESSEL"],[64,71,"GPE"]]}],["Conveyance hither for the Packets on board the Ternate, on more serious",{"entities":[[47,54,"VESSEL"]]}],["My Vessel the Recovery which ought to have left Bombay about the 15th. July and even",{"entities":[[14,22,"VESSEL"],[48,54,"GPE"],[65,75,"DATE"]]}],["the August Mail vessel must according to all reasonable Chances and Calculation",{"entities":[[4,10,"DATE"],[11,22,"VESSEL"]]}],["have reached Bushire before the expiration of last month and by a conrition that",{"entities":[[13,20,"GPE"],[46,56,"DATE"]]}],["Europe and Constantinople rendering necessary the dispatch of a vessel to India and",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE_ORG"],[11,25,"GPE_ORG"],[74,79,"GPE"]]}],["the present Departure of the Panther on her returning",{"entities":[[29,36,"VESSEL"]]}],["Voyage to Bombay",{"entities":[[10,16,"GPE"]]}],["The Panther wilt touch at Bushir for the express purpose of",{"entities":[[4,11,"VESSEL"],[26,32,"GPE"]]}],["receiving your advices for the Honble the President in Council who will no doubt be extremly",{"entities":[[31,62,"TITLE"]]}],["anxious to receive intelligence from you of the safe arrival at Bushier of the Ternate and",{"entities":[[64,71,"GPE"],[79,86,"VESSEL"]]}],["of the probable immeadate consequences in Persia of the melencholy fate of the tate Hadgee",{"entities":[[42,48,"GPE_ORG"],[84,90,"TITLE"]]}],["Kullul Khawn",{"entities":[[0,12,"PERSON"]]}],["I request however expedite the Departure from Bushire for the Presidency",{"entities":[[46,53,"GPE"],[62,72,"ORG"]]}],["of the Panther as much as may be possible, and Itake upon Myself the Responsibitity of",{"entities":[[7,14,"VESSEL"]]}],["strongly recommending to you to retain the Ternate at Bushire untill replies to Your",{"entities":[[43,50,"VESSEL"],[54,61,"GPE"]]}],["Communications to the Court of Tehran unequivocally convince you that the accident",{"entities":[[22,37,"GPE_ORG"]]}],["which deprived the late Persian Embassador of life will not expose the Honble Companys",{"entities":[[24,42,"TITLE"],[71,86,"ORG"]]}],["Servants, Property and Credit at Bushirer to Risk and Danger",{"entities":[[33,41,"GPE"]]}],["question for however unavoidable it may have been it is to be feard that the Persian",{"entities":[[77,84,"NORP"]]}],["Monarch, ignorant of the Honble Correctness of the British Government in India may",{"entities":[[0,7,"NORP"],[51,78,"GPE_ORG"]]}],["idly attribute it to Design or to a want of requisite arrangements at the Presidency for",{"entities":[[74,84,"ORG"]]}],["I have hitherto concealed the Death of Hadgee Khullul",{"entities":[[39,53,"PERSON"]]}],["Khawn from the knowledge of every Person here except that of WDay, but as it is a",{"entities":[[61,65,"UNKNOWN"]]}],["the Propriety of explaining it to the Deacaseds Agents and Relation, Aga Mahomed Nebie",{"entities":[[69,86,"PERSON"]]}],["by which Conduct you may extend his means of receiving the Khawns Property in",{"entities":[[59,65,"TITLE"]]}],["Persia and of preventing Injury to the Fortune and Family of a Person who in his life",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"]]}],["time rendered some essential Services to the British Nation thereby establishing claim",{"entities":[[45,59,"NORP"]]}],["Maghil 6th. October",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"],[7,19,"DATE"]]}],["Samuel Manesty",{"entities":[[0,14,"PERSON"]]}],["1802",{"entities":[[0,4,"DATE"]]}]]}