{"classes":["TITLE","VESSEL","PERSON","GPE","ORG","QUANTITY","UNKNOWN","GPE_ORG","DATE"],"annotations":[["The Officer Commanding the Marine Battn.",{"entities":[[4,11,"TITLE"],[27,39,"VESSEL"]]}],["Bombay",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"]]}],["Sir ,",{"entities":[]}],["I have the honor to inform you",{"entities":[]}],["that in consequence of the unsubordinate and re=",{"entities":[]}],["=fractory conduct of Hossein Mahomed and Je=",{"entities":[[21,36,"PERSON"]]}],["=hangeer Khan two Privates belonging to the Ma=",{"entities":[[9,13,"TITLE"],[18,26,"PERSON"]]}],["=rine Battalion Native Infantry under your",{"entities":[[6,31,"TITLE"]]}],["Command and attached to the Escort of this",{"entities":[[28,34,"ORG"]]}],["Residency I have been under the necessity of send=",{"entities":[[0,9,"ORG"]]}],["=ing them on board the H.C.C. Clive and receiving",{"entities":[[23,35,"VESSEL"]]}],["two Seapoys by name Shaik Moideen and Hossen",{"entities":[[4,11,"TITLE"],[20,33,"PERSON"],[38,44,"PERSON"]]}],["Khan from the detachment of the Marine",{"entities":[[32,38,"ORG"]]}],["Battalion serving on board that Vessel in the",{"entities":[]}],["room of the above two Individuals with whose",{"entities":[]}],["conduct I have frequently had reason to be dis=",{"entities":[]}],["=satisfied._",{"entities":[]}],["The particular instance which",{"entities":[]}],["rendered it incumbent on me to remove the Sea=",{"entities":[]}],["=poys in question from the Residency Guard and",{"entities":[[27,42,"ORG"]]}],["which took place about two months ago during",{"entities":[[23,33,"QUANTITY"]]}],["my absence from Bushire was Hossen Mahomed",{"entities":[[16,23,"GPE"],[28,42,"PERSON"]]}],["using the most gross and insulting language",{"entities":[]}],["to Subidar, Shaik Moideen who commands the",{"entities":[[3,10,"TITLE"],[12,25,"PERSON"]]}],["Detachment on his sending for him from his",{"entities":[[0,10,"ORG"]]}],["quarters to inquire whether he was able to go-",{"entities":[]}],["on duty, as he had been in the sick list for a",{"entities":[]}],["considerable time_ In this outrageous and",{"entities":[]}],["violent conduct he was joined and abetted",{"entities":[]}],["by Jehangeer Khan and at last they came to",{"entities":[[3,17,"PERSON"]]}],["such length that the Subadar was obliged to",{"entities":[[21,28,"TITLE"]]}],["place them both in confinement a short time",{"entities":[]}],["afterwards on Bagnack Ramnack the Naique",{"entities":[[14,29,"UNKNOWN"],[34,40,"TITLE"]]}],["of the Guard attempting to interfere between",{"entities":[[7,12,"ORG"]]}],["Hossein",{"entities":[[0,7,"PERSON"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["104",{"entities":[]}],["Hossin Mohumed and a man he was quarreling",{"entities":[[0,14,"PERSON"]]}],["with he was knocked down and repeatedly -/-",{"entities":[]}],["struck by the former Individual._",{"entities":[]}],["Not having the power of inflicting",{"entities":[]}],["a punishment adequate to the riotous and",{"entities":[]}],["violent behabiour of these two Sepoys I consi=",{"entities":[[31,37,"TITLE"]]}],["=dered most advisable to adopt the measures",{"entities":[]}],["above narrated and in enclosing Copy of a",{"entities":[]}],["Vide Page letter to Captn. Betham Commander of the -/-",{"entities":[[20,33,"PERSON"],[34,43,"TITLE"]]}],["95",{"entities":[]}],["Clive on the subject of their Transfer with his",{"entities":[[0,5,"VESSEL"]]}],["reply thereto for your information",{"entities":[]}],["I have & ca, & ca ;",{"entities":[]}],["Bushire Resy.",{"entities":[[0,12,"GPE_ORG"]]}],["/Signed/ E.G. Stannus",{"entities":[[9,21,"PERSON"]]}],["26th. Decemr. 1826._",{"entities":[[0,20,"DATE"]]}],["Rest._",{"entities":[[0,6,"TITLE"]]}],["To",{"entities":[]}],["Captain C.B. James",{"entities":[[0,18,"PERSON"]]}],["Military Paymaster",{"entities":[[0,18,"TITLE"]]}],["Bombay",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}