{"classes":["PERSON","TRIBE","GPE_ORG","REL","LOC","GPE","QUANTITY","MONEY","VESSEL","TITLE","ORG","UNKNOWN"],"annotations":[["which, whether the Boats are large or small, the sum of one hundred rupees is to be",{"entities":[[68,74,"MONEY"]]}],["paid to the Honble Company and afoo Two Rupees to the Secretary that issues them",{"entities":[[12,26,"ORG"],[40,46,"MONEY"],[54,63,"TITLE"]]}],["the passes are to have the Honble Companys Seal affixed to them, to be signed by the Agent",{"entities":[[27,42,"ORG"]]}],["or Resident and undesigned by the Secretary- boats that wear english colours and",{"entities":[[3,11,"TITLE"],[34,44,"TITLE"]]}],["are not furnished with this pass, will be made prizes of, wheresoever are Cruizers",{"entities":[]}],["meet them-",{"entities":[]}],["A merchant Boat offering to Bushire",{"entities":[[28,35,"GPE"]]}],["gives us the opportunity of sending you this letter",{"entities":[]}],["We",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["12",{"entities":[]}],["We are",{"entities":[]}],["Bussora",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["the 30th. Decr. 1767",{"entities":[]}],["Your Loving Freinds",{"entities":[]}],["Reid 17 Jany. 1768 of Country Boat",{"entities":[[22,34,"VESSEL"]]}],["Henry Moore",{"entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]}],["George Skipp",{"entities":[[0,12,"PERSON"]]}],["To",{"entities":[]}],["Mr. James Morley",{"entities":[[0,16,"PERSON"]]}],["Resident at Bushire ..",{"entities":[[0,8,"TITLE"],[12,19,"GPE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["Since our last letter to you of the 9th January",{"entities":[]}],["of Express Boat, we have arrived by the Tyger, duplicate of yours of the same date and",{"entities":[[3,10,"VESSEL"],[40,45,"VESSEL"]]}],["original under the 13th- the original of the former inclosing a bill of Exchange on Coja",{"entities":[[84,88,"PERSON"]]}],["Stephan for 2400KY, and your accounts for December is not come to hand.",{"entities":[[0,7,"PERSON"],[12,18,"MONEY"]]}],["The Dolphin Sohoonor is now despatched to your",{"entities":[[4,20,"VESSEL"]]}],["place; purposely to convey you this letter; with one for Carim Caun herein inclosed, which",{"entities":[[57,67,"PERSON"]]}],["you well forward to Schiras with all convenient speed_ the Sohooner we would have you",{"entities":[[20,27,"GPE"],[59,67,"VESSEL"]]}],["return immediately to us ..",{"entities":[]}],["Shouts two or more of the Honble Companys",{"entities":[[26,41,"ORG"]]}],["cruizers, designed for this place, arrive at Bushire, you will immediately dispatch the",{"entities":[[45,52,"GPE"]]}],["smallest of them hither, with any advices they may being from the Residency- the",{"entities":[[66,76,"GPE_ORG"]]}],["others you will keep with you untill further orders..",{"entities":[]}],["Provided the Merchants will come into your",{"entities":[]}],["proposal of taking off BroadCloth, when they are only in want of Serpets, it will",{"entities":[]}],["doubtless be a very beneficial measure to the Honble Company: were we the only",{"entities":[[46,60,"ORG"]]}],["dealars in Cloth in the Persian Dominions, this, might succeed, but in the present",{"entities":[[24,41,"GPE_ORG"]]}],["situation of affairs we fear it will not; we direct you however to attempt it, in",{"entities":[]}],["case you are suceessful to continue it; we have already sent you our resolutions",{"entities":[]}],["on the subject of not ordering any woollens from Bushire to Bussora",{"entities":[[49,56,"GPE"],[60,67,"GPE"]]}],["We have recieved by the Tyger Rupees",{"entities":[[24,29,"VESSEL"],[30,36,"MONEY"]]}],["three Thousand/3000/ agreable to your Invoice",{"entities":[[0,20,"QUANTITY"]]}],["Mr. Skipps return to Schirass/ for which",{"entities":[[0,10,"PERSON"],[21,30,"GPE"]]}],["place he is to set out, as soon as the Bombay Grab, can be get ready for the sea/",{"entities":[[39,45,"GPE"]]}],["we are in great hopes, will remove all impediments relative to the Trade of",{"entities":[]}],["Bushire",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"]]}],["As the opening of Mr Bouyears private",{"entities":[[18,29,"PERSON"]]}],["letters",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["13",{"entities":[]}],["letters may be useful towards the management of her affairs at Bushire, we",{"entities":[[63,70,"GPE"]]}],["direct you to open them, recommending to you, at the same time, to use the",{"entities":[]}],["communications in them with that prudence and Caution, which so delicate",{"entities":[]}],["a bussiness requires",{"entities":[]}],["We are",{"entities":[]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}