{"classes":["PERSON","TRIBE","GPE_ORG","REL","LOC","GPE","QUANTITY","MONEY","VESSEL","TITLE","ORG","UNKNOWN"],"annotations":[["Orange",{"entities":[]}],["Purple",{"entities":[]}],["By. 60",{"entities":[]}],["120 By",{"entities":[]}],["Mr. James Morley",{"entities":[[0,16,"PERSON"]]}],["Resident",{"entities":[[0,8,"TITLE"]]}],["Bushire",{"entities":[[0,7,"LOC"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["The Revenge and Esex agreable to what we wrote",{"entities":[[0,20,"VESSEL"]]}],["you under the 15th Instant, now proceed to your place, and with the other Vessels",{"entities":[]}],["are to wait for orders from the Agency.",{"entities":[[32,38,"ORG"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["18",{"entities":[]}],["Mr George Green is embarked on board the Essex, and",{"entities":[[0,15,"PERSON"],[41,46,"VESSEL"]]}],["on his arrival is to act jointly with you in the management of our Honble",{"entities":[[67,73,"TITLE"]]}],["affairs conformable to the Rules of the Service he has received his Salary to the 2 Instant ,",{"entities":[]}],["and Diet to the end of last month, but no allowance for his Passage..",{"entities":[]}],["We are",{"entities":[]}],["Bombay Castle",{"entities":[[0,13,"GPE"]]}],["Your Loving Friends",{"entities":[]}],["24 January 1768",{"entities":[]}],["Thomas Hodges",{"entities":[[0,13,"PERSON"]]}],["Daniel Draper",{"entities":[[0,13,"PERSON"]]}],["James Ryley",{"entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]}],["R H Boddam",{"entities":[[0,10,"PERSON"]]}],["Benjamin Jervis",{"entities":[[0,15,"PERSON"]]}],["Nathaniel Stackhouse",{"entities":[[0,20,"PERSON"]]}],["To",{"entities":[]}],["Mr James Moorley",{"entities":[[0,16,"PERSON"]]}],["at Bushire",{"entities":[[3,10,"GPE"]]}],["Resident",{"entities":[[0,8,"TITLE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["By the Wolfe Gallivat we this day received your Letter",{"entities":[[7,21,"VESSEL"]]}],["of the 12 Instant inclosing Copy of your address to the Presidency Via Muscat, your Letter",{"entities":[[56,66,"ORG"],[71,77,"GPE"]]}],["to Mr Skipp, and your monthly accounts for February.",{"entities":[[3,11,"PERSON"]]}],["You have acted very properly in opening our",{"entities":[]}],["Superior packet by that Vessel, and transmitting a Copy there of, with the list of",{"entities":[]}],["our forces to Mr Skipp at Schyrass_ You will act in the same manner on",{"entities":[[14,22,"PERSON"],[26,35,"GPE"]]}],["the arrival of the Revenge and Eagle which we hourly expect from the",{"entities":[[19,26,"VESSEL"],[31,36,"VESSEL"]]}],["Presidency: and we hope by this means, the Plenipotentiary negotiations with",{"entities":[[0,10,"ORG"]]}],["Carim Caun, will not only be accelarated but benefitted likewise.",{"entities":[[0,10,"PERSON"]]}],["Your refusal of paying double Rent to Shaikh",{"entities":[[38,44,"PERSON"]]}],["Nassirs Nacheel for the rent of our Factory at Bussora and referring the dispute",{"entities":[[0,15,"PERSON"],[47,54,"GPE"]]}],["to Mr Skipp in order for him to settle with Shaikh Nassir at Schirass concerning",{"entities":[[3,11,"PERSON"],[44,57,"PERSON"],[61,69,"GPE"]]}],["it, we think it the most proper method you could take for its adjustment.",{"entities":[]}],["As we see no probability for sometime to come",{"entities":[]}],["of disposing, of the Woollens already in our Warehouses, and those daily expected",{"entities":[]}],["we think it for our Employers interest that you should not send us the 120",{"entities":[[71,74,"QUANTITY"]]}],["Bales designed for this Agency, especially as by our Accounts many difficulties",{"entities":[[0,5,"QUANTITY"],[24,30,"ORG"]]}],["will attend it, and as, there is some probability, that the Cauns demands",{"entities":[[60,65,"TITLE"]]}],["for Woollens will shortly be considerable",{"entities":[]}],["We do not see the necessity there was for your or Mr",{"entities":[[50,52,"PERSON"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["19",{"entities":[]}],["Mr Skipps addressing the Honble the President and Council by",{"entities":[[0,9,"PERSON"],[25,31,"TITLE"],[36,45,"TITLE"],[50,57,"ORG"]]}],["and there hazardeng the Expence of several hundred Rupees to our Hon",{"entities":[[43,57,"MONEY"],[65,68,"TITLE"]]}],["by sending an express Boat across to Bombay, in case no accidental",{"entities":[[37,43,"GPE"]]}],["offer- your letter to the Presidency, is itself, a full conviction, that nothing very",{"entities":[[26,36,"TITLE"]]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}