{"classes":["UNKNOWN","PERSON","ORG","VESSEL","GPE","DATE"],"annotations":[["in which our Honble Employers were concerned could give rise, on your side to",{"entities":[[13,29,"UNKNOWN"]]}],["this Extraordinary zeal- had Mr Skipp favoured us with a Copy of his letter to",{"entities":[]}],["to the governor and Council, we might perhaps have been convinced of the necessity",{"entities":[[7,15,"UNKNOWN"],[20,27,"ORG"]]}],["of the dispatch; but as it is, we must own it has somewhat surprised us-",{"entities":[]}],["You will receive this by the Dolphin Schooner ,",{"entities":[[29,45,"VESSEL"]]}],["which is dispatched express with the inclosed packet to the Presidency in hopes of",{"entities":[[60,70,"ORG"]]}],["her overtaking the Betsey ketch before her arrival at or departure from Bushire-On",{"entities":[[19,31,"VESSEL"],[72,82,"GPE"]]}],["the arrival of the Schooner You will immediately return her to us; and/should the",{"entities":[[19,27,"VESSEL"]]}],["Betsy have sailed from Bushire/ the packet likewise-",{"entities":[[0,5,"VESSEL"],[23,31,"GPE"]]}],["We are",{"entities":[]}],["17 March 1768",{"entities":[[0,13,"DATE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["Your Loving Friends",{"entities":[]}],["Henry Moore",{"entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]}],["To",{"entities":[]}],["James Moorley",{"entities":[[0,13,"PERSON"]]}],["Mr",{"entities":[]}],["Resident",{"entities":[[0,8,"UNKNOWN"]]}],["Bushire",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["Your letter of the 11th February of Bombay Grab",{"entities":[[19,32,"DATE"],[36,47,"VESSEL"]]}],["and of the 26th of Express Boat have been surely received the former enclosing our monthly accots.",{"entities":[[11,15,"DATE"],[19,31,"UNKNOWN"]]}],["for January",{"entities":[[4,11,"DATE"]]}],["The Betsey Ketch Captain Stennits now proceeds",{"entities":[[4,16,"VESSEL"],[17,33,"PERSON"]]}],["to the Presidency, and as she will touch at your place in her way thither, you will by",{"entities":[[7,17,"ORG"]]}],["her advise the Governor and Council of way occurence relative to the trade of Bushire",{"entities":[[15,23,"UNKNOWN"],[28,35,"ORG"],[78,85,"GPE"]]}],["In one of our former Letter we directed you to",{"entities":[]}],["send us up the smallest of the Cruizers that might arrive at your Part from Bombay",{"entities":[[76,82,"GPE"]]}],["and to detain the remainder that order however is now countermanded, and you",{"entities":[]}],["are directed to send them all up to Bussora/ unless the orders from Bombay direct",{"entities":[[36,44,"GPE"],[68,74,"GPE"]]}],["otherwise/ after opening their Packets and extracting every thing that relates to our negotiations",{"entities":[]}],["with Carim Caun, which Extracts as we before wrote you, are to be sent to Mr Skipp",{"entities":[[5,15,"PERSON"],[74,82,"PERSON"]]}],["at Schyrass",{"entities":[[3,11,"GPE"]]}],["During",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}],["During Mr Shipps residence at Scherass should he",{"entities":[[7,16,"PERSON"],[30,38,"GPE"]]}],["to exdent to you for woolens, you will comply therewith, and on his return",{"entities":[]}],["he will account to you for the amount",{"entities":[]}],["We are",{"entities":[]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["arch 1768",{"entities":[[5,9,"DATE"]]}],["Recd the 22",{"entities":[[5,11,"DATE"]]}],["Your Loving Friends..",{"entities":[]}],["Henry Moore",{"entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]}],["To",{"entities":[]}],["Mr",{"entities":[]}],["James Morley",{"entities":[[0,12,"PERSON"]]}],["Resident",{"entities":[[0,8,"UNKNOWN"]]}],["at Bushire-",{"entities":[[3,11,"GPE"]]}],["Sir",{"entities":[]}],["I was favoured with your letter of the 12th Instant",{"entities":[[39,51,"DATE"]]}],["with the several papers therein mentioned agreable to your desire endeavour to",{"entities":[]}],["settle the Rent of the Caravansera with Shaik Nassir, and procure a writing from",{"entities":[[23,34,"UNKNOWN"],[40,52,"PERSON"]]}],["him, that no more than the Sum stipulated shall be annualy demanded, the",{"entities":[]}],["reason it was not settled last year agreable to the then Resident desire, was, that",{"entities":[[57,65,"UNKNOWN"]]}],["as the Embassy was not attended with the Success the Agent and Council were",{"entities":[[7,14,"ORG"],[53,58,"UNKNOWN"],[63,70,"ORG"]]}],["satisfied with, and from there orders. I had the greatest reason to conclude the",{"entities":[]}],["factory would be entirely withdrawn, it therefore rendered it needless to stir in",{"entities":[]}],["the affair ..",{"entities":[]}],["",{"entities":[]}]]}