{"classes":["TITLE","ORG","VESSEL","GPE","PERSON"],"annotations":[["this Extraordinary zeal- had Mr Skipp favoured us with a Copy of his letter to",{"entities":[[29,37,"PERSON"]]}],["to the governor and Council, we might perhaps have been convinced of the necessity",{"entities":[[7,15,"TITLE"],[20,27,"ORG"]]}],["You will receive this by the Dolphin Schooner ,",{"entities":[[29,45,"VESSEL"]]}],["which is dispatched express with the inclosed packet to the Presidency in hopes of",{"entities":[[60,70,"TITLE"]]}],["her overtaking the Betsey ketch before her arrival at or departure from Bushire-On",{"entities":[[19,31,"VESSEL"],[72,82,"GPE"]]}],["the arrival of the Schooner You will immediately return her to us; and/should the",{"entities":[[19,27,"GPE"]]}],["Betsy have sailed from Bushire/ the packet likewise-",{"entities":[[0,5,"VESSEL"],[23,31,"GPE"]]}],["Henry Moore",{"entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]}],["James Moorley",{"entities":[[0,13,"PERSON"]]}],["Resident",{"entities":[[0,8,"TITLE"]]}],["Bushire",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"]]}],["Your letter of the 11th February of Bombay Grab",{"entities":[[36,42,"GPE"]]}],["and of the 26th of Express Boat have been surely received the former enclosing our monthly accots.",{"entities":[[19,31,"VESSEL"]]}],["The Betsey Ketch Captain Stennits now proceeds",{"entities":[[4,16,"VESSEL"],[17,33,"PERSON"]]}],["to the Presidency, and as she will touch at your place in her way thither, you will by",{"entities":[[7,17,"TITLE"]]}],["her advise the Governor and Council of way occurence relative to the trade of Bushire",{"entities":[[15,23,"TITLE"],[28,35,"ORG"],[78,85,"GPE"]]}],["send us up the smallest of the Cruizers that might arrive at your Part from Bombay",{"entities":[[76,82,"GPE"]]}],["are directed to send them all up to Bussora/ unless the orders from Bombay direct",{"entities":[[36,44,"GPE"],[68,74,"GPE"]]}],["with Carim Caun, which Extracts as we before wrote you, are to be sent to Mr Skipp",{"entities":[[5,15,"PERSON"],[74,82,"PERSON"]]}],["at Schyrass",{"entities":[[3,11,"GPE"]]}],["During Mr Shipps residence at Scherass should he",{"entities":[[7,16,"PERSON"],[30,38,"GPE"]]}],["Henry Moore",{"entities":[[0,11,"PERSON"]]}],["Mr",{"entities":[[0,2,"PERSON"]]}],["James Morley",{"entities":[[0,12,"PERSON"]]}],["Resident",{"entities":[[0,8,"TITLE"]]}],["at Bushire-",{"entities":[[3,11,"GPE"]]}],["settle the Rent of the Caravansera with Shaik Nassir, and procure a writing from",{"entities":[[23,34,"ORG"],[40,52,"PERSON"]]}],["reason it was not settled last year agreable to the then Resident desire, was, that",{"entities":[[57,65,"TITLE"]]}],["as the Embassy was not attended with the Success the Agent and Council were",{"entities":[[7,14,"ORG"],[53,58,"TITLE"],[63,70,"ORG"]]}]]}