{"classes":["COMMODITY","DATE","GPE","GPE_ORG","LOC","MONEY","ORG","NORP","PERSON","QUANTITY","REL","STRUCTURE","TITLE","TRIBE","UNKNOWN","VESSEL"],"annotations":[["Public account for the express Conveyance to the Presidency of a Packet from the Honble the",{"entities":[[49,59,"ORG"],[81,87,"TITLE"]]}],["Secret Committee, It is my wish that she should not be detained by you at Bushire beyond",{"entities":[[0,16,"ORG"],[74,81,"GPE"]]}],["the final Sales at Busheer of the Consignments of Woollens per Ships Governor Duncan",{"entities":[[19,26,"GPE"],[50,58,"COMMODITY"],[69,84,"VESSEL"]]}],["and Diamond in 1801 particularly explaining to Me the terms of them, as well in respect",{"entities":[[4,11,"VESSEL"],[15,19,"DATE"]]}],["Maghil near Bussora",{"entities":[[0,6,"GPE"],[12,19,"GPE"]]}],["the 5th. August 1802",{"entities":[[4,20,"DATE"]]}],["received per Shannon on the",{"entities":[[13,20,"VESSEL"]]}],["Samuel Manesty",{"entities":[[0,14,"PERSON"]]}],["12th. Augst.",{"entities":[[0,11,"DATE"]]}],["Wm Bruce Asst.",{"entities":[[1,9,"PERSON"],[10,14,"TITLE"]]}],["The Honble the Governor",{"entities":[[4,23,"TITLE"]]}],["& President",{"entities":[[2,11,"TITLE"]]}],["Honble Sir_",{"entities":[[0,11,"TITLE"]]}],["I had the Honor to inform your Honble Board sometime ago that Europe Clothes of a Pea",{"entities":[[31,43,"ORG"],[62,76,"COMMODITY"]]}],["Green Colour was not saleable at the Market In the year 1800 several of that came here which",{"entities":[[56,60,"DATE"]]}],["was sent back to the Presidency as there was no prospect of them being sold_",{"entities":[[21,31,"ORG"]]}],["By the Goods received by the Ships Diamond & Governor Duncan several Bales of",{"entities":[[35,42,"VESSEL"],[45,60,"VESSEL"]]}],["Clothes of that Colour came here by mistake Amongst the Bales of Scarlet Long Ells as marked",{"entities":[[65,82,"COMMODITY"]]}],["damaged Goods & one along with several Bales of Scarlet Long Ells sold & carried to Yedz",{"entities":[[48,65,"COMMODITY"],[84,88,"GPE"]]}],["Also when I sold the Broad Cloth the Bales where all spend; amongst which in leu of Scarlet",{"entities":[[21,32,"COMMODITY"]]}],["Superfine; three Bales of Fine Pea Green where found- I cannot say whether this mistake",{"entities":[[0,9,"COMMODITY"]]}],["originated in packing the Bales at Europe or in Shipping them at Bombay_ but as",{"entities":[[35,41,"GPE"],[66,73,"GPE"]]}],["I sold the Goods for Scarlet Colours & the Brown Cloth for Superfine; I have to request your",{"entities":[[11,36,"COMMODITY"],[43,68,"COMMODITY"]]}],["Honble Board will direct the Invoice to be forwarded that I may be able to settle their proper",{"entities":[[0,12,"ORG"]]}],["price with the Merchants If any more Bales of Pea Green should be found amongst",{"entities":[[37,55,"COMMODITY"]]}],["the Bales of Long Ells now here, I shall acquaint your Honble Board of it",{"entities":[[4,22,"COMMODITY"],[55,67,"ORG"]]}],["I have the honor to acknowledge the receipt of your letter dated the 9th.",{"entities":[[65,72,"DATE"]]}],["April 1802 & agreeable to it respecting Mr Waring I have fully followed- I wrote to the",{"entities":[[0,10,"DATE"],[40,49,"PERSON"]]}],["Governor of Sheraze & Isphahawn informing them that a European Gentlemen",{"entities":[[0,31,"TITLE"],[54,72,"PERSON"]]}],["be molested on his tour; I also wrote to the Shaike Nassur Khawn Governor of Bushier",{"entities":[[45,64,"PERSON"],[65,84,"TITLE"]]}],["as He was then at Sheraze_",{"entities":[[18,26,"GPE"]]}],["Colonel Harcourt in Charge of a Packet for Europe from the Most",{"entities":[[0,16,"PERSON"],[43,49,"GPE"]]}],["Noble the Governor General arrived here on the 4th June & left this again on",{"entities":[[0,26,"TITLE"],[47,55,"DATE"]]}],["the 7th. He directed that I work and send on Europe in five days by land to Bussora",{"entities":[[0,8,"DATE"],[45,51,"GPE"],[76,83,"GPE"]]}],["to inform Mr. Manesty of his being on his way there with which I of course complied",{"entities":[[10,21,"PERSON"]]}],["trafic is carried on but in English Ships as the Country Vessels dare not venture out of",{"entities":[[28,41,"VESSEL"],[49,64,"VESSEL"]]}],["there Parts for of the Baniattaba Arabs_ By land the whole of the Country is in disturbances",{"entities":[[24,41,"NORP"]]}],["indeed the Caravans from here to Sheraze are frequently plundered, which is never the case",{"entities":[[33,40,"GPE"]]}],["when the King is feared-",{"entities":[[9,13,"TITLE"]]}],["I have the honor to forward three Months Accounts of this Factory",{"entities":[[58,65,"STRUCTURE"]]}],["Bushire 14th August",{"entities":[[0,7,"GPE"],[8,19,"DATE"]]}],["1802",{"entities":[[0,4,"DATE"]]}],["Hunble Sir.",{"entities":[[0,10,"TITLE"]]}]]}